Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpurohit, I am the founder
of Family First Financial Services, I am an MBA Finance and have been working in the corporate sector for 14 years
and today I am presenting to you that in March 2025, SBI Life Insurance
has launched its third policy keeping in mind the education and marriage of children.
In March 2025, before this, they had launched a plan called Young Achiever where
you used to get guaranteed returns. After that, they launched a product called
Future Star where you get bonus based returns and
the product that has been launched now is called Smart Scholar Plus, which is a Uli policy where
you will get market linked returns, that is, a guaranteed product has also been launched for you.
Bonus based product has also been launched and
keeping in mind those who like high risk high returns products, in market linked returns, you
have launched a product called Smart Scholar Plus, where if the parents who pay the premium
die, then the premium will be waived off. If there is a disability in an accident,
then also the premium payment will be waived off. On maturity, the child will definitely get natural
cover You will also get insurance Plus you
will get inbuilt accidental cover benefit You will get more than 10 funds for investment where you
will get share market based returns which can be up to 10, 12, 15, 20 and if needed,
you can also withdraw money after 5 years without taking a loan and you
will not have to pay back to the company the money you have withdrawn So watch this video completely, if you
like the video then
definitely subscribe to my YouTube channel Anil Rajpurohit FFFS You will get more insurance related videos which
will help you in your financial planning Talking about the eligibility criteria of this policy,
because this is a policy for a child, the age of the child
can be between zero to 17 years The proposer who will be the parents Where life assured
has been mentioned here, again and again we will talk about life assured i.e. parents Whenever in the future
whenever I say life ahead, it means we are talking about parents and child means we
are talking about the child, so life The minimum entry age of the assured parents
can be between 18 to 50 years. Talking about maturity age,
the minimum maturity age of the child should be 18 years and the maximum maturity age
for the child is 25 years and if the age of the parents reaches 65 years, then
you can take the maximum maturity age up to that age of whichever of the two reaches 25 or 65 first.
Talking about the policy term, you
can select any policy term between 8 years to 25 years. 8, 9, 10, 15, 20, 25. In this way, you can take any policy term. You
can also make the premium payment regularly. You can also take a single premium policy
and you can also take the option of limited pay, if you want to increase the premium by 5 years or
if you want to run the policy for 20 years, you can still run it. 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10 Policy term
minus one. You will get the option of limited pay in this. The minimum premium in single pay
will be 75000. If you opt for regular or limited pay option apart from single premium,
then the minimum premium will be ₹5000000 per annum. You
can also avail 10 times insurance cover and you will also get inbuilt accidental cover in this policy. Talking about
the maturity benefit in the policy, since it is a unit linked insurance policy
, here you get the fund value on maturity, that is, the fund in which
you invest in the share market based fund, you
will get the fund value based on the performance of that fund. It can be at 8, it can be at 10, it can be at 12, it can be at 5. There
can also be negative returns because it is share market based but
in the long term, if you have seen the past performance of the share market, it has always
been positive. So, the returns of the market, whichever fund you select,
you will get the fund value as per that fund. Talking about death benefit,
here in death benefit, suppose the life assured dies, which is There is a proposer
who is the father, for example, here sum assured or 105 per cent of total
premiums paid, whichever is higher, will be received immediately, rest of the premiums
will be waived i.e. SP Life Insurance will pay it itself and there will be no
mortality charges or any other charges of any kind on the rest of the premiums which the company is paying
and you will also get maturity based on the market performance
i.e. the child will get maturity but if the child dies in the policy
then there will be no insurance cover and the parent who is the proposer will
Father can continue to pay premium in this policy and take the policy till maturity
or if he wants to terminate the policy, he
can do so. For additional benefit which is an in-built benefit, you
do not have to pay any additional premium for it. So the first benefit is called accident
benefit. What will happen in accident benefit is that if there is death due to accident or
if there is total permanent disability in an accident, then you will get insurance cover equal to your basic sum assured
which can go up to a maximum of 50 lakhs. So suppose
you have purchased a policy of ₹ 50 lakhs and you are paying premium of ₹ 50 lakhs
in which there is 10 times insurance cover, then there will be a natural cover of 10 lakhs, then you
will also get additional inbuilt accidental cover benefit of 10 lakhs. Now suppose if
there is death in an accident, then you will get the natural cover of 10 lakhs plus the accidental cover of
10 lakhs. If you get that too, you will get a total of 20 lakhs.
In case of death in an accident, the money is given in lump sum. But
even if you do not die in an accident but have total permanent disabilities,
you will still get ₹1 lakh accidental cover at the rate of ₹1 lakh every year for the next 10 years. That is, you
get a lump sum amount in case of accidental death. In case of accidental total permanent disabilities,
you get money in installments for the next 10 years. The feature is called
premium
payer waiver benefit, that is, if the parents die, the premium payment will be waived. All the remaining premiums
will be sent by SBI Life Insurance and the child will get the maturity amount.
For this, you do not have to pay any additional premium. But if the child dies first,
then this premium payer waiver benefit does not work and it will stop.
This rider will stop. But suppose both the parents
and the child die. If both of them die, then the legal heirs in the family,
i.e. the heirs, will get the benefit. In this policy, you
are also given the benefit of loyalty addition, which
can be up to 1% of the average fund value of your last 2 years i.e. 24 months. Let us assume that you
have taken a policy term of 20 years, then you will get loyalty addition benefit in the 8th year, 11th year, 14th year, 17th year
and 20th year. For the rest of the different policy terms,
you can see in the chart here that in which four years the loyalty
addition benefit will be added to the fund value in your account. In this plan, you
are also given the benefit of switching, if you want to switch from one fund to another,
then it is free of cost. Here you can switch from one fund to another. For
example, when the market is going up, you
are investing in equity fund, but suppose the market is coming down, then you
What will you do , will you shift to bond fund or money market fund
, you will switch from one fund to another, there is no cost to pay for this or you
can do it free of cost sitting at home through internet or you can also do it by going to the company or
you can do free of cost switching here by taking help from your agent advisor,
here you are also given the option of premium redirection, suppose you
have a premium which you were earlier paying in equity fund but now you are thinking that it
is a future premium, you have to pay it in some other fund, suppose you
have to pay in bond fund, then you can do that redirection that in the coming future
premium, you want to invest in some particular other fund, then this
option is also given in this policy, in this policy you will also
get the benefit of parcel withdrawal, partial withdrawal is a liquidity option which
is very useful, like in the Covid time you must have seen that people needed money and suppose
there were some other type of plan, then you would not have withdrawn money there. There you would
have to take a loan, which means you have to pay the loan to the company on your own policy, but
in this policy you do not need to take a loan. After the lock-in period of 5 years, you
can withdraw up to 15% of its loan value. You can withdraw this money twice a year,
maximum two times in a year if your policy term
is 10 years or less, then you can withdraw five parcels. But if the policy term
is 10 years or more, then you can withdraw 10 parcels and maximum two times in a year.
You can withdraw parcels with a minimum amount of Rs. 5,000 and
you can withdraw a maximum of 15 parcels at a time and in partial withdrawal if you
If we talk about the total premium that you will pay, suppose you
have paid ₹ 1 lakh as premium every year and your fund amount
is 7 lakh or 8 lakh, then you will have to pay at least . lakh i.e. % of the total premium paid i.e. 5 lakh
. You will have to keep Rs. 1 lakh with the RBI.
If you wish to withdraw the remaining amount as a parcel withdrawal, you can withdraw it. You do not have to pay it back, nor do you
have to pay any interest to the company, nor do you have to take it as a loan. This
is your money which you can utilize like an ATM after 5 years, if you wish to do so.
This is a liquidity option for you. In this Uli policy, charges are levied.
Allocation charges are at 6 in the first year, then at 45. From the sixth year onwards, allocation charges
will be at 1 and after 11 years, there are no allocation charges in this policy. Suppose you
are purchasing a 20-year regular pay policy, then after 11 years,
you do not have to pay any allocation charges. Talking about the fund management charges here, the
charges of those who manage the funds for you in the policy, if
you take equity related funds, then there will be charges up to 1.35 but if you take money market fund,
then only You will be charged 0.25%. There will also be a charge for mortality i.e. insurance
cover, but that is on sum at risk. Talking about fund options,
a total of 10 funds have been provided. I am telling you only three in the screenshot,
which are equity funds. Like equity fund, to 300 fund, equity optimizer fund
, in this way money market fund, bond fund, in this way a total of 10 funds have been provided in this company,
where you can invest in equity from 80% to 100%. If
you want to invest 100% in debt bull fund, you can do so. The fund
performance of this company has also been very good. Different funds of the company have
performed returns of more than 13% in the past. I will also tell you a little about the fund performance.
Talking about fund performance or value, there is historical data which
is of Fund Builder. I have taken the equity fund of SBI Life from 14 March 2010 to
11 March 2025. Data has been extracted where the NAV on 11th March 2025
is 183 which was around ₹ 5 in 2010. NVT of 55 on 15th March 2010
has become 183 in 2025. This is because the market is low right now. If we look at it some time back,
the NAV used to be around 00. If we talk about 3rd January 2025, then it
was 203 at that time, which means 3 has become 203 now. So your money has become almost six times.
So in this way, if you look at your fund performance, your money has become six times in just 15 years.
So here you have got a good return of 13% or more. In this way, you can see
in different funds because when you look at the benefit, then
according to the rules of IRDA, you will not see more than 8% in the table, but the actual
return can be either more or less than the table, but
by taking the past performance into account, If you see, positive returns have been more, which
has been more than 8%. For example, if we talk about a blue chip fund, the blue chip
fund of SBI Life Insurance, which is of August 25, 2024, if I talk about where
an investment of 80% in equity is an investment of 80 to 100%,
you can invest from zero to 20% in a debt fund, you can
also invest in a money market fund, the fund manager will decide that he will keep 80 as a minimum,
but whether to go between 100 or not, the fund manager will decide. Now,
in the equity fund where he has invested, there
is money of about 93%, that has been invested in your equity fund, what the fund manager has
actually done is where he has invested 0.29% in SK Automobiles,
he has invested 0.98% in Bajaj Auto, in this way he has invested 0.32% in Ro Motor Co.
In this way, he has invested in a company.
If you look at auto etc., they have invested 7.61 per cent where
you can see these different companies in India, in capital goods, they
have invested 8 per something per cent, in cement company it is 1.52 per cent, that is, if you look at different companies of different sectors,
then their investment has also been told
, what percentage has been invested in
which sector , look here, details of particular company have also been mentioned,
in financial services, your investment is up to 27 per cent, in FMCG there is an investment of 6.6.64 per cent,
in oil and gas your investment of 5 per cent has been done by the company, the fund
manager has done it, so here you can see the whole etc. in money market fund, so
A lot of investment of 6.4% has been made, so the investment you are making in SBI,
SBI also invests your money in many companies and many sectors,
where you will get good returns, after tax you will get a return of lakhs.
Now let us understand the benefit illustration of SP's Smart Smart Scholar Plus
Plan, which is a unit link insurance policy. Here you will see that the person
whose age is 35 years is purchasing the policy, the child's age is 5 years, the policy
term is 20 years, the premium payment is 20 years, he will pay an annual premium of Rs.
10 lakhs and his natural insurance cover will also be Rs. 10 lakhs and his accidental cover will also
be Rs. 1 lakhs. Where he is investing in different funds, equity fund,
equity optimizer fund, growth fund, balance fund, here you will see
that he has invested in different percentages, where how much FMC charges will be levied, that
is also mentioned, whether the risk level is high, medium to high, low to medium or a low risk fund,
you can also see that here as per your need. According to that, the fund that you want to select, you
have to select one fund, you have to select two, you can select it in part B.
If you understand this plan in details, here the customer is paying Rs. 1 lakh each, he
has taken the option of regular pay for 20 years, where the premium allocation charges will be deducted for 10 years
, will not be deducted for 11 years, it will be deducted in the first year in 6 years, then your allocation
charges of Rs. 45, then those allocation charges will be there in Rs. 1 per month, mortality charges
are also mentioned here, policy admin charges,
there are charges for the inbuilt rider of waiver of premium here and the inbuilt disabilities rider etc. are also mentioned,
loyalty additions are as I told you, which the company provides you
on the eighth year, which you get on the 11th year, on the 13th year, on the 14th year,
on the 17th year and on the 20th year, you will get the fund value, as you must be seeing the fund value here,
the last fund value last You will see 1% of the daily fund value of 24 months
as loyalty addition here. You
can also see the column of benefit for insurance cover and you can see the column of fund value here. You
will see the maturity of 37 lakh
6438. As per the IRDA rules at this age, the actual fund performance will be as per the mentioned % and
the actual returns will be according to that. After 5 years,
if one wants to make partial withdrawal, he can do that too. Now I will try to give another example
where you are the same customer, he is
purchasing at the age of 35 years, he has a 5 year old child, the policy term is 20 years but
this time he is taking the premium payment term only for 5 years and he pays the premium on ₹ 1 lakh
because you get tax free returns on investment up to ₹ 1 lakh. Here
you will have an insurance cover of 25 lakh and accidental insurance cover of 25 lakh as well. And if
you want to invest in different funds here, you can do that.
You can also invest in AF. Here you will notice that you
are paying only for 5 years, after that you do not have to pay. And here you
can also see the benefits. Here the loyalty addition benefit which the company
will give you has also been mentioned here. And if you see the fund value here, you
will get Rs. 33 lakh which will be tax free. I am repeating the actual fund performance again and again,
which can be different because this is % and 4 per cent as said by the government. So
if you show the return of 4 per cent and 6 per cent, then the charge has been deducted in the beginning, then
the returns will be negative. The actual fund performance
depends on your fund. I told you that equity funds have
given returns up to 135 per cent. There are some funds since 2010, their returns are even better than this.
Since 2001, SBI Life Insurance is there. If you want to take high risk high return then
you can purchase this policy. Let's talk about other benefits and features of the policy.
Surrender benefit: If you want to surrender this policy after 5 years and
take the entire money, then you can take it. After the first year or second year, if you
do not pay the premium, the policy will go to discontinue fund and
after the fifth year, if you wish to withdraw that money also, you can withdraw it. The returns of discontinue fund
are comparatively very low because they
are not actively participating in the market. Talking about policy loan, since it
is a Uli policy, it is a unit linked policy, so loan is not available here, but
you can avail the benefit of partial withdrawal. After 5 years, tax is deducted in ATC through income tax.
You will get the benefit and the returns
on the investment up to ₹ 101D of income tax
will be tax free if you invest in mutual fund in the same policy then up to 125% of the returns
are taxed but here the returns on the investment up to ₹ 101D
are zero taxable. Talking about the grace period and revival
period in this policy, the grace period will be of 30 days, the free look period will also
be of 30 days and the revival period will be of 3 years. If for some reason you
are unable to pay the premium on time then you
can activate the policy again within 3 years by paying late fees etc. So finally if I suggest then this
is an excellent plan. In today's date customers are preferring equity based returns over high
risk high returns that too keeping in mind the education and marriage of children
because it is flexible. You can withdraw money whenever you want,
after 5 years. So what happens in normal traditional policies,
suppose you have taken a policy term of 25 years, but you
want to withdraw money for your daughter's marriage after 18 years, you cannot do it, you
have to surrender it all at once, which is the surrender option there. If I talk about traditional policies, but
in Uli policies you can surrender anytime, so whatever your fund value
is, you can withdraw the entire amount, so this is a very flexible one, plus you have
the option of waiver of premium, that even if the parents whose premium is to be increased die,
the policy continues, if you
are investing in mutual funds etc., then who will pay the next installment in SIP, no one will pay, but here
the next installment will be paid by SBI Life Insurance itself because the parents who
were to pay have died, so there is no need to pay premium for the child, but
it will come on maturity, accidental cover has been given to you as an additional in-bill,
no separate premium has to be paid, the premium payment is also made by you. You can fill the period from 5 years
to as many years as you need. The maturity amount on premium up to ₹ lakh is
tax free. Option of partial withdrawal is given. 10 funds
are given for you to invest and there is also a brand like SBI, so if
you want to purchase this policy from me, you can contact me on the number given below
9909 4034 12. If you want to consult whether similar plans
are available in other companies or not, are they better than this, how many funds have been
given to you for investment in them, is their fund performance better than this fund,
then you can consult and compare that and then contact me on my mobile number.
If you like the video, then say as much
Jai Hind as possible.